Guide to the A. H. Raskin Papers WAG.259
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
A. H. Raskin Papers
1940-1994
WAG.259
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
4.0 linear feet in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, 5 oversize flat boxes.
A. H. Raskin (1911-1993) was a noted labor journalist and editor. This collection consists primarily of columns Raskin wrote about labor for the New York Times between 1940 and 1976.
Raskin, A. H. (Abraham Henry), 1911-
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Existence and Location of Copies note
A. H. Raskin's columns can be found in back issues of the New York Times and digital copies can be found in the New York Times Article Archive.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: General Files, 1940-1994
Series II: Scrapbooks, 1961-1976
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The A. H. Raskin Papers were donated by Marjorie Raskin in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.064.
Historical/Biographical Note
A. H. Raskin (1911-1993) was a noted labor journalist and editor. Born in Edmonton, Alberta, he graduated from City College in 1931 and joined the New York Times as a labor reporter in 1934. In 1942, Raskin joined the U. S. Army and served as chief of the Labor Branch of the Industrial Services Division. He returned to the New York Times upon his discharge at the end of the war. In 1952, Raskin wrote a series of articles about racketeering in labor unions. The articles won numerous awards and prompted the American Federation of Labor to establish an anti-racketeering committee. During the New York newspaper strike of 1963, Raskin researched and wrote a 15,000 word article that appeared the day after the strike ended. It remains a highly regarded work of journalistic objectivity in the face of great difficulty. He retired from the New York Times in 1977, but continued writing. In 1990, Raskin suffered a stroke which caused him to develop aphasia (difficulty in producing or comprehending spoken or written language). During the remaining years of his life, Raskin was involved in educating others about aphasia, most notably in his moving New York Times op-ed piece "The Words I Lost" (Sep 19, 1992).
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists primarily of columns Raskin wrote about labor for the New York Times between 1940 and 1976. Columns from 1940-1959 are photocopies, while those from 1961-1976 are original clippings in large scrapbooks. In addition, there are some non- New York Times writings on labor, as well as material on Raskin's struggle with aphasia.
Related Archival Materials
Further materials on A. H. Raskin can be found in the New York Times Company Records, Abraham H. Raskin Papers at the Manuscripts and Archives Division of the New York Public Library.
AFL-CIO.; American Federation of Labor.; Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.).; New York Times Company.; Raskin, A. H. (Abraham Henry), 1911-; Raskin, Marjorie; Aphasia.; Clippings (information artifacts); Journalists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Labor journalism |z United States.; Labor movement |z United States |y 20th century.; Labor union journalism |z United States.; Labor unions |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Newspaper columns.; Scrapbooks.
- Series I: General Files, 1940-1994
  - Aphasia, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1974-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographical Material, 1991-1994; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - City College New York Alumni Association Card, 1988/89 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center: Printed Material, 1988-1989; undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memo re: Robert P. Brindell, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - National Symposium on Stroke and Quality of Life, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notes and Research Materials: Labor, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notes: General, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photograph of Raskin, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Raskin, Marge: "What Constitutes True Love for an Aphasiac?" (Tribute to AHR), circa 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Writings: Aphasia, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Writings: Draft of New York Times Column, Dec 17, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Writings: Joseph S. Fay, Notes and Draft of Article on, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jan-Jun 1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jul-Dec 1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jan-Jun 1952 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jul-Dec 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jan-Jun 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jul-Dec 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1954 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jan 1 1957-Mar 14 1957 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Mar 15 1957-Jun 28 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jul-Dec 1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jan-Jun 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Jul-Dec 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (photocopies), Dec 20, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Writings: Non- New York Times, 1957-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Writings: Review of Collision by Kenneth C. Crowe, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series II: Scrapbooks, 1961-1976
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1963-1965 (Box 3, Volume 2)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1966-1967 (Box 4, Volume 1)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1968-1969 (Box 4, Volume 2)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Volume 1)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Volume 2)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1974 (Box 6, Volume 1)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1975 (Box 6, Volume 2)
  - Writings: New York Times Columns (Scrapbook), 1976 (Box 7, Volume 1)